# **Dhanapal Jayapandi**

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

11675 Rainwater Dr, Alpharetta, GA 30009

□ (+1) 678-666-0066 | ★ djay93.github.io | □ djay93 | □ betakođer | ♥ @betakođer

## Summary\_

Software engineering manager, architect, and development expert with over 10+ years of professional experience. Extensive track record in designing and implementing elegant and pragmatic solutions for enterprise applications. History of excellence in digital transformation, cloud, data engineering, architecture, and technical leadership. Growth mindset kept by seeking new challenges and learning new skills, languages, and tools. Aim to utilize my analytical and technical skills to increase the productivity and performance of the organization.

# **Work Experience**

Amdocs Inc. Atlanta, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Oct. 2011 - Present

- Managed large-scale Enterprise applications in production environments: Mobility CRM (30K users/800K calls per day), Uverse CRM (20K users/400K calls per day), Business eBill (2M users/10B bills per month), and MDE (2M campaigns per day).
- Designed, architected, and developed a cloud-native business intelligence and reporting platform that allows customers to gain insight from diverse billing data sources and simplify the business processes.
- Designed and developed microservice-based bill payment and bill presentment APIs, leading to a highly-reliable and 99.99% availability of the online billing portal.
- Implemented automated deployment pipelines for microservices running as Docker containers using Jenkins, Ansible and Maven.
- Overhauled web applications from server-side rendering view technologies (JSP/Struts) to client-side rendering view technologies (Angular), leading to increased usability and mobile responsiveness.
- Conceptualized, redesigned and optimized ETL processor to extract invoices data from billing data feed into NOSQL datastore Cassandra.
- · Spearheaded development of Mass data load system, MDE, to help business with mass campaigns, adjustments, and BOGO offers.
- Revamped MDE to reduce system coupling; directed parallelized algorithms to improved the performance by 500%.
- · Managed product deliverables, project deadlines, system availability, technology infrastructure, system security, and business proposals.
- Promoted Agile transformation efforts to improve team velocity by 2x times instituted retrospectives, continuous integration, code reviews and automated testing.
- · Initiated proof of concept efforts for new technologies and tools to help with pre-sales and eliminate technical debt.
- Led a team of software engineers to design and implement software projects, generating over \$2MM+ in annual revenue.

Amdocs Inc. St. Louis, USA

Formulated implementation and ongoing maintenance plan for Enterprise CRM applications.

- Designed and developed an intuitive and easy-to-use Dispute and Adjustment module for an estimated 50% efficiency gain in operations and potential net savings of \$400K per month to the customer.
- Managed overall service infrastructure focusing on high-availability, business continuity, and system performance.
- Identified security risks, performance issues, technical debts, and recommended changes to simplify application's on-going maintenance.
- Mentored junior software developers helping with knowledge on best practices, software development techniques, and CRM implementation.
- Promoted to Software engineering manager within 24 months due to strong performance and organizational impact ahead of schedule by 24 months.

#### **Amdocs Development Ltd**

Limassol, Cyprus

Oct. 2009 - Sep. 2011

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

DEVELOPMENT EXPERT

July. 2006 - Oct. 2009

- Developed and maintained Amdocs CRM application for several clients AT&T Mobility, AT&T Uverse, Excelcom, Telstra, and Isabella.
- Analyzed new features from customers and proposed both business and technology solutions to implement in the existing application.
- Upgraded the CRM from v12.5 to v6.0 suite and v6 to v7.5 Amdocs suite for Cingular/AT&T Mobility.
- Implemented Amdocs CRM v7.5 for Isabella, Kazakhstan government, to manage e-service tickets.
- Authored proof-of-concept to show the business value of Amdocs CRM to DishNET, Telstra, and Excelcom.
- · Provided bug fixes, performance fixes, query optimizations, and usability improvements.

Amdocs Development Ltd Limassol, Cyprus

SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT Oct. 2004 - Jun. 2006

- Designed, developed and deployed large-scale CRM for TOnline and VFUK.
- Implemented a logging framework for TOnline backend applications to logs messages in Eclipse Common Base Event (CBE) format.
- · Analyzed and fixed performance issues and functional defects in existing CRM implementations.
- Provided bug fixes for Amdocs eCare Integration APIs, Orion release.
- Involved in the testing of Orion and Omega releases of Amdocs CRM.

HCL Technologies Chennai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

June. 2003 - Oct. 2004

- Developed DART, Developers Automated Regression Tool, for testing pricing, usage and billing APIs of Convergys Atlys Billing System.
- Enhanced the digital knowledge base of Atlys Billing with latest technologies.

## Key Skills \_\_\_\_\_

Languages	Java, J2EE, JavaScript	t (ES5/ES6), Typescript,	C++, Python,	PHP, Perl, Unix Shells, AWK
-----------	------------------------	--------------------------	--------------	-----------------------------

**Backend** Spring framework, Spring Boot, Node.js, Express, Flask, Laravel

**Frontend** Angular, React.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass

**Databases** Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & Containers Kubernetes, AWS (EKS, Lambda, EC2, IAM, S3), Azure, Serverless Framework

CI/CD Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Git, Nexus, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven

**Systems** Red Hat Linux 5/6/7, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, Weblogic, Apache Tomcat EE, Nginx

**Domain Knowledge** CRM, ETL, BI & Analytics, Order management, Electronic bill payments, Self-service portals, Campaigns

**Others** Nagios, Vagrant

### **Certifications**

2020 AWS Associate Solutions Architect, AWS

2020 AWS Cloud Practitioner, AWS

2019 **SAFe Agilist**, Scaled Agile Framework

2013 Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI

2008 **Sun Certified Java Developer**, J2SE 5.0

2006 Sun Certified Web Component Developer, J2EE 1.4

2005 **Sun Certified Java Programmer**, J2SE 5.0

### **Education**

#### **College of Engineering (Anna University)**

Guindy, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jun. 1999 - May. 2003

• Received Gupta Scholarship, 1999 - 2003, for academic excellence in the computer science department.